<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Yeo Lab</title><link>yeolab.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="yeolab.github.io/feeds/all.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 11:46:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><item><title>Gene Yeo, Ph.D.</title><link>yeolab.github.io/blog/gene-yeo-phd</link><description>&lt;h2&gt;Degrees&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MBA&lt;/span&gt;, University of California, San Diego, 2008&lt;br&gt;
Ph.D., Computational Neuroscience, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MIT&lt;/span&gt;, 2005&lt;br&gt;
B.S., Chemical Engineering, University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign 1998&lt;br&gt;
B.A., Economics, University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign 1998&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Gene Yeo is a scientist, entrepreneur, inventor and expert in the area of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RNA&lt;/span&gt;, genomics and neurological diseases.  Dr. Yeo obtained a bachelor of science in chemical engineering and a bachelor of arts in economics from the University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign and a masters degree in business administration from the Rady School of Management at the University of California, San Diego.  Funded by the prestigious Lee Kuan Yew Graduate Fellowship from Singapore, Dr. Yeo earned a Ph.D. in Computational Neuroscience from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology under the joint guidance of Dr. Tomaso Poggio and Dr. Christopher Burge.  Using comparative genomics and statistical learning theory Dr. Yeo pioneered new computational approaches to attack the problem of splicing and splicing-mediated gene regulation.  In 2005 Dr. Yeo was appointed the first Junior Fellow at the Crick-Jacobs Center for Theoretical and Computational Biology at the Salk Institute under the mentorship of Dr. Fred Gage and Dr. Sean Eddy.  Dr. Yeo’s collaborative nature has generated successful projects and grants with experts in neuroscience and neurodegeneration (Dr. Fred Gage and Dr. Don Cleveland), &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RNA&lt;/span&gt; processing (Nobel Laureate Dr. Phillip Sharp, Dr. Manuel Ares, Jr, Dr. Brenton Graveley, Dr. Xiangdong Fu and Dr. Amy Pasquinelli) and virology (Dr. Deborah Spector).  In late 2008, Dr. Yeo was appointed an Assistant Professor in the Department of Cellular and Molecular Medicine at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UCSD&lt;/span&gt;.  In 2011, Dr. Yeo was awarded the Alfred P Sloan Fellowship in recognition of his work in computational molecular biology.  Since 2003, Dr. Yeo has authored over 50 peer-reviewed publications, invited book chapters and review articles.  Dr. Yeo has successfully authored 3 and co-authored 2 grants from the California Institute of Regenerative Medicine totaling $7.2 million.  The National Institute of Health, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ALS&lt;/span&gt; Association, Genentech and Roche Pharmaceuticals also fund Dr. Yeo’s work. Dr. Yeo actively serves as a bioinformatics and business consultant to biotech and pharmaceutical companies, and has been involved with start-ups in the biotechnology space.  Dr. Yeo reviews for many scientific journals including Science, Cell and Nature, and is on the Editorial Board of the journals Cell Reports and Cell Research. Dr. Yeo is an Adjunct Professor at the National University of Singapore and a visiting researcher at the Molecular Engineering Laboratory under Nobel Laureate Sydney Brenner’s auspices. Dr. Yeo was a Sword of Honor recipient (the highest honor) in Officer Cadet School in 1999 and has served in the Singapore Navy as a Naval officer.  In his free time, Dr. Yeo sails and is an avid amateur athlete racing in Ironman distance races and&amp;nbsp;marathons.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 11:46:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:,2015-07-29:yeolab.github.io/blog/gene-yeo-phd</guid></item><item><title>Olga Botvinnik</title><link>yeolab.github.io/blog/olga-botvinnik</link><description>&lt;h2&gt;Degrees&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M.S., Bioinformatics, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UC&lt;/span&gt; Santa Cruz, 2012&lt;br&gt;
S.B., Biological Engineering, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MIT&lt;/span&gt;, 2010&lt;br&gt;
S.B., Mathematics, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MIT&lt;/span&gt;, 2010&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Olga Botvinnik is a Bioinformatics and Systems Biology Ph.D. student at University of California, San Diego (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;UCSD&lt;/span&gt;). Previously, she earned two &lt;span class="caps"&gt;S.B.&lt;/span&gt; degrees from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in Mathematics and Biological Engineering while participating in a variety of research experiences in Prof. Martha Bulyk, Dr. Sean Eddy, Prof. David Gifford and Prof. Sebastian Seung&amp;#8217;s labs.  After graduating &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MIT&lt;/span&gt;, Olga worked at the Broad Institute in Cambridge, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MA&lt;/span&gt; with Dr. Jill Mesirov and developed an algorithm to find alternative activators in cancer. She then attended the University of California, Santa Cruz, where she created a single-cell &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RNA&lt;/span&gt;-sequencing differential expression analysis pipeline in Prof. Nader Pourmand’s laboratory. As a graduate student at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UCSD&lt;/span&gt;, and is interested in the genomics and transcriptomics of single cells, especially in the heterogeneous populations of cancer, neuroscience and development. Olga is funded by the National Defense Science and Engineering Graduate Fellow and was a Hertz Fellowship Finalist. In her free time, Olga enjoys design, yoga, photography, and playing&amp;nbsp;cello.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:,2013-06-01:yeolab.github.io/blog/olga-botvinnik</guid></item></channel></rss>